Original Air Date: 7/24/14
Translated and subbed by: BlueMentaiko
Disclaimer: The translation is not guaranteed to be perfect. Some words and phrases have been slightly altered so it makes more sense in English. Since this is a one-person project, please be understanding of any mistakes I may have made. Thank you!
It started with this one word...
Let's all do a part-time job to repay the fans!
Work Part-Time And
Repay the Fans
HKT48 was created in Hakata in 2012!
The reason why these girls are nationally active is because they have fans who support them very hard!
Conceived by HKT48's theater manager, Sasshi-kun, the idea is that the girls will earnestly work part-time
and use the money they earn to create an HKT original umbrella to repay the enthusiastic fans who visit the theater.
This is an unprecedented show!
This time, the member who will work part-time is...
I'm HKT48, Team KIV's Fuchigami Mai!
Working part-time today is the honor student who is my-pace, but friendly and reliable.
It's Fuchigami Mai-kun.
She's new to working part-time.
What is your image of a part-time job?
My image of a part-time job is... All my friends from school work part-time,
and a lot of them serve customers.
But I have no idea what I'm going to do.
Well, you're new to this whole part-time job thing, so it's hard to image anything, huh?
We'll announce what part-time job Fuchigami-kun will be doing today!
Open!
Mentaiko factory!
Eh? Mentaiko?
Mentaiko Factory
Earnest Part-Time Job
You will work earnestly at a mentaiko factory!
Your image of a mentaiko factory
What kind of job are you imagining?
It's a factory, so you'd wear white work clothes that covers your whole body.
But I came here looking like this. This is the
outfit I'm proud of.
Personally, I think it's quite cute.
Mhm, yes, tell the fans how eager you are.
Yes, today I'm going to work at a mentaiko factory.
I'd like to do my best for the fans!
I'm off!
Amazing. This is what mentaiko is like.
HKT48's serious part-time job documentary!
This time, Fuchigami Mai will earnestly work part-time at a mentaiko factory!
Everything is a first experience!
Speed battle!!
By working part-time, she'll learn the difficulty of
working and earning money.
She'll grow both as an idol and as a person. Don't miss it!
I'm my-pace...
Work hard with high pace!
HKT Shakariki 48!
Yes, try saying, "Don!"
Mentaiko Factory
Earnest Part-Time Job
All right, today's stage is Mentaiko's Chikumaya.
They produce mentaiko with careful attention to the ingredients and the seasonings.
The delicious, delicious mentaiko made here will be served on everyone's dining table.
Mentaiko on top of warm rice. It's irresistible!
An appointment with the person in charge
Excuse me.
- Yes.
I'm Tanaka, the factory manager of Chikumaya.
This person is in charge of the factory. He is Tanaka-kun!
Your hairstyle is rocking.
And this is Yoshimaru-kun from the quality management division.
Before getting to work, let them explain the important points.
At this company, hygiene management is the most important.
Yes, hygiene!
Everyday, they thoroughly check your physical condition and the length of your fingernails. Amazing.
Took quite a long time to thoroughly check
There are a lot of important points.
Yes, since it's going to enter the customer's mouth.
- I understand.
This is a lot of responsibility.
This is what I'll wear?
I won't look like I'm in HKT anymore...
That's true. We won't know it's Mai-kun if she looks like this. That means!
Yes, since you're done getting ready, we will head to the factory.
Understood.
I look like a young bird now, is that ok?
There's no point if we can't see her face.
This time, she will wear a special idol version.
You look surprisingly good! Piyo, piyo, piyo.
Part-Time Job Start
You'll use the roller here.
I use the roller on my head.
You can never bring dust or germs into the factory.
From here, a sanitation check awaits Mai-kun.
All right, next.
It's in here, right?
- Yes.
Do it evenly on your body, please.
Scary, scary, scary, scary!
You will once again take off any dirt on your body here.
Go ahead.
Amazing. I'm going to be sucked in.
One, two, three, four, five.
All right, one, two. One, two.
Then your thumb- one, two, three.
Amazing, doesn't it smell like mentaiko?
- Because it's a mentaiko factory...
Put on gloves.
It's like I'm going to perform surgery.
Eh, amazing.
And then you enter the factory.
The inspection that makes her say, "This too?" is finally complete.
Finally to the factory...
Just doing this is tiresome.
Thank you for today.
Amazing.
This many people work here?
Amazing. They're all women.
This is where we keep our raw ingredients.
This is the pollock roe.
This is before it's sold in stores.
- Then it's not flavored yet?
Nope.
Then we flavor it, add seasoning, and make it good.
That's right. They take this unflavored roe, cover it with their original seasoning, and let it cure for 72 hours. That will make delicious mentaiko.
We want her to start working from the seasoning step, but!
Unfortunately, it's a company secret.
Mentaiko dish, measure
Package the finished product
Inspect the finished product
With that said, her work starts after the seasoning is done.
In the morning, she will receive training.
However, she's given only one hour. It's quite tight!
Mai-kun's helper is...
Ishibashi-san!
This is Ishibashi-san who is in charge of this area.
Please take care of me.
- Please take care of me.
Mai-kun's trainer is the Johnny's-loving Ishibashi-kun.
Without her work clothes... Oh, pretty girl!
Please take care of Mai-kun.
First, please get the trey.
Take the trey.
It's thin, so try getting one.
Can't take it off...
My clumsiness is going to be exposed.
- I'll have you measure out 65 grams.
Amazing. This is what mentaiko is like?
Not yet, not yet.
It went over.
You have to make one every ten seconds or so.
Ten seconds? Eh?
Watch how fast a pro does it
Despite how slow Mai-kun works at getting the treys, let's see how fast Ishibashi-kun is...
Amazingly, 10 seconds! Just meet!
This is a professional!
By the way, it took Mai-kun 30 seconds.
This is the trey from before.
Put it in like this.
I feel like I can do this.
- Yes, try putting it in.
Ah! That surprised me!
Crap, crap!
I'm rushing.
Ah, surprising!
We'll have you do this in the afternoon, too, so please remember it.
Next, you'll check the back of these to see if there's a sticker.
And then you'll check to see if there's an error.
Is this a speed battle as well?
- That's right. Each one is...
I'm my-pace.
- You can't say you're my-pace for this.
It doesn't matter? I understand.
That's right. This checking process is simple, but very important.
It's going to keep coming, it's going to keep coming.
Work accurately and treat it valuably!
I'm starting to get hungry.
- You're already hungry?
You haven't done much yet.
Keep going!
It's ok!
They said we're done.
- Really?
Yes, we're done.
For now, we're done with with work.
End of work training
We'll head up for lunch now.
She's quite my-pace.
About Fuchigami
But you can't keep saying you're my-pace on the job.
It's a speed battle. I always do things on my own pace...
But when it comes to work, it doesn't matter.
Break
What? Lunch already?
Well, well, this is what she was looking forward to.
How long have you been working here?
Three years this year.
We joined in the same year.
Then are you two good friends?
We do hang out.
- That's nice.
What is the reason you joined HKT?
The talk turns to the topic of HKT Fuchigami Mai
Rather than an idol, I liked singing.
I thought HKT was nice. Plus it's my hometown so I thought it'd be nice.
The stage performance always starts at 6:30.
The theater performance's inside story
But five minutes prior to that, everyone is still brushing their teeth.
Behind the scenes.
We enter the stage three minutes before and sing like two minutes after that.
Eh, that's amazing.
But the staff always scolds me.
They tell me to hurry up.
In order to repay the fans I'm indebted to, I'd like to do my best in the afternoon as well.
In the afternoon, a big crisis...
Mentaiko Factory
Earnest Part-Time Job
Mentaiko dish, measure
Package the finished product
Inspect the finished product
The afternoon work will begin.
Finally, this is the real performance.
Use everything you learned in the morning and do your best, Mai-kun!
Measure out the material.
Understood.
- Do your best.
Make sure it weighs between 65g to 69g and pack it into the trey
Fast.
Once all the mentaiko in the basket between them is gone, this work is done.
Was not good at this work in the morning
Let's see the difference in speed between Mai-kun and the person to the left of her.
Ah, Mai-kun!
You're already falling behind at the part where you take off the plastic trey. Oh!
The person to your left has already completed one. Hurry, hurry!
As expected, the person to her left is a veteran. Her rhythm is good, she's already done.
Mai-kun, you still haven't completed one!
Hurry, hurry! But you have to make sure it's accurate.
As expected from a veteran! You're fast!
Fast.
Just on my side, the amount hasn't decreased, right?
What a nice person.
From here, we will fast forward by 30 times the speed.
As expected, the person on the left is fast. She keeps going. Mai-kun, do your best, too!
89 Packs
44 Packs
Are we done?
I'll check it.
The way you arranged it is the same, so it's ok. It's fine.
Yatta!
No, no, this is all thanks to your senpai to the left, right?!
This...
I did it a lot last time, so I have a little bit of confidence.
Next is inspection duty! She has to check to see if there is a label on the bottom of the pack. It's an important duty!
See? It's properly stuck on there!
Hmm, Mai-kun who appears to be confident. Show us your cool side!
See? See? The packs keep coming.
Rhythm, the rhythm is important!
Oh, you're properly checking it. You're starting to get used to handling it.
Is there really one without a label?
This one! It doesn't have a label.
Discovered a label-less one
Is this a bad one?
Yes.
Those come down. Put the one without the label here.
Mai-kun, nice! 100 points! Now you have some momentum going into the next process.
I'll have you fold boxes here.
Here, they quickly assemble the cardboard box.
It wasn't in her schedule, but it's obvious. It's work, so doing it is natural
It seems like we'll be able to film a funny clip. Let's see how she's doing.
Ishibashi-san handles it well. As expected from a veteran.
She's rhythmical and speedy!
Watching it feels good.
Mai-kun, are you ok?
Come on, quicken your pace!
Do it!
Ishibashi-san does 50 in 10 minutes
You're a pro at this.
All right, I did it!
- You did it.
Fuchigami does 25 in 12 minutes
I'm glad.
All right, next, that again, please.
Eh, this is hard.
After this, a huge crisis...
Begins to pack the flash frozen mentaiko
I'm going to leave for a bit.
Please do your best.
Alone from here
- I'm going to do this alone?
I'll try my best.
Will it be ok?
Crap, I'm alone.
I need to do my best.
It fell.
Ah, Mai-kun, what are you doing?
The trey that lost a few grams need to be remeasured.
Eh, this is hard.
I knocked it over...
I mixed it up.
- Do you know which one is which?
This too.
This side is ok.
We'll remeasure this.
It goes back to get remeasured
I'm sorry.
More than in a hurry
The spaces in-between open up
Excuse me!
Umm...
When I do it quickly, it ends up spilling. When I try to do it carefully, this space in-between ends up opening.
Is there a problem with this?
That is...
There's a secret at the back.
The answer to her anxiousness is at the back
- Is that so?
I was really anxious about that.
We throw away the ones that weren't filled.
- You throw it away?
These are actually the ones Mai-san left unfilled.
That many?
It's this.
- Eh, I'm sorry.
You left these unfilled today.
The unfilled treys were being disposed
This becomes a cost. Do it so there's no waste.
It's the most important task.
- Is that so?
Then...
how can I reduce waste?
That's right. There's a "start" and "stop" button.
She couldn't keep up with the normal speed. However, she assertively looks for a solution and tries to learn it.
She's my-pace, but reliable. That's Fuchigami Mai.
Restarts with the advice in mind
Ah, wait!
Stop!
I'm glad. Just barely safe.
Dangerous, dangerous.
Start!
I'm done!
I'm sorry to bother you while you're working.
Um, some time ago, I let a lot of these packs go through. How is it now?
It's decreased. There isn't even one.
- Really? Thank you.
- I'm sorry for allowing so many to go through a while ago.
Did it decrease?
It seems so. Thank you.
- That's good.
Splendid. Clap, clap, clap!
Mai-kun, I think you grew quite a bit in just one day.
And then, after she finishes with the packing duty...
Part-Time Job Complete
I'm done!
Done!
It's these two loads.
In 6 hours, she created about 700 packs of the product
It's 16 cases, so that's about 700 packs.
They will be shipped to various places.
I'm happy.
I hope it gets delivered safely.
Starting from the afternoon, she got really used to it.
I think she was the best at it.
I think you were able to learn various things.
- Yes, I tried my best. It was fun.
I'm glad.
Thank you for today.
- Thank you for today.
Thank you for today. We're going to give you your pay for today, so please, this way.
Excuse me.
Hello.
Thank you.
Thank you for your effort.
This is your part-time pay for today.
Part-time payment
- Thank you.
This is my first time receiving a salary for working part-time.
- Ah! Is that so?
Please use it wisely.
Please.
- Yes, thank you very much.
Thank you for today!
I received it. For Fuchigami Mai.
I received 4,000 yen.
Ever since I was little, my parents used to tell me that receiving money isn't an easy thing.
But I was really able to absorb the difficulty of it today.
The fans who are students who come to handshake events and such can't afford it with just their allowance,
so they work part-time and kindly come to our theater performances.
I think this is really important money.
Something is in there.
Ah, a 500 yen coin.
That means it's forty...
4,500 yen.
Oh, so 100 yen coins are included, too?
She experienced the difficulty of working.
The happiness and sense of fulfillment she was able to obtain...
Having experienced this, we'll certainly meet a better Fuchigami Mai.
Mai-kun, what does working part-time mean to you?
Working is hard is how I felt.
That thing a little while ago was a 500 yen coin.