Original Air Date: 7/10/14
Translated and subbed by: BlueMentaiko
Working at a ramen store is harder than being an idol.
Disclaimer: The translation is not guaranteed to be perfect. Some words and phrases have been slightly altered so it makes more sense in English. Since this is a one-person project, please be understanding
of any mistakes I may have made. Thank you!
It started with this one word...
Let's all do a part-time job to repay the fans!
Work Part-Time
To Repay the Fans!
HKT48 was created in Hakata in 2012!
The reason why these girls are active nationwide is because they have fans who support them very hard!
The idea to earnestly work part-time to repay the fans was designed by HKT48's theater manager, Sasshi-kun.
This unprecedented, super great show started last week!
The important point is deciding how to best repay the fans with the money they earn from working.
I had the members think of the best way!
I'd like something that we can do that will repay everyone.
Like a stand.
A stand might be fun!
Yeah, like an HKT48 stand.
Then how about we turn the seats in the theater into something more extravagant. All of it.
We hand out juice to the fans who come to the theater.
That's good. It might be delicious.
Hmm, various ideas were suggested, but they were all thrown out.
But the members get on board with Lovetan's nice idea.
An umbrella.
According to the staff, there are some fans who head home wet from the rain,
so maybe like a spare umbrella.
- Ah, that's really good.
Lovetan, 100 points!
With the money they'll earn from working, they'll make an original umbrella for the fans who head to the theater despite the rain and wind.
With that, I'll now announce the member who will work part-time!
That member is...
The first person chosen to work part-time is Miyawaki Sakura-kun, who amazingly came in 11th place at this year's AKB48 Senbatsu Sousenkyo.
Of course you've never worked part-time before, right?
For that Sakura-kun, this is where she will earnestly work!
Ramen store!
Ramen Store
Earnest Part-Time Job
You'll work seriously at a ramen store!
Hard...
HKT48's serious part-time job documentary!
On the last episode, you saw the idol, Miyawaki Sakura, work busily at a store just before it opens.
My arm is in pain.
Finally Tonight!!
We're going to open!
We'll see her work earnestly in the store that has turned into a battlefield!
- If you don't hurry up, we're not gonna make it in time!
Battlefield Kitchen!
Miyawaki's Surprising Truth!
In a world she has never set foot into, can she accomplish all the things she was tasked with!?
Impossible.
Huh? What do you mean it's impossible?
HKT Shakariki 48!
The show's title, Shakariki, doesn't have a particularly deep meaning. That's kinda bad.
At a Ramen Store
Second Part
Earnestly Work Part-Time
The store that Sakura-kun is earnestly working for is Hakata Ikkousha, located inside JR Hakata Station.
They're proud of their deliciously-made soup. Look at it? Uwaa!
Makes you want to eat it, huh?
On busy days, they serve more than 500 people. It's a really busy, really popular store!
It's finally the opening! Before that, she participates in the morning assembly to make her heart one with the other staff.
Things like this is important.
Thirteen Minutes
Before Opening
Since it's the weekend, I think it'll be busy, but let's do our best to serve all the customers.
- Yes!
I came here to work part-time. I'm Miyawaki Sakura.
So that I don't stand in the way, I'd like to work hard with everyone to liven up Ikkousha-san!
Please take care of me!
Please take care of me today, everyone.
It's like...
My mood is rising.
Preparing the Store For Opening
Prepping Tables, Cleaning
Prepping the Condiments (Ginger, Garlic, Etc.)
Wipe Dishes, Place Pitchers
Morning Assembly
Opening
Tasks in the Kitchen
Serving Customers, Catering, Cleaning Up
Dish-Washing, Preparation
These are Sakura-kun's work duties.
Go to step 2!
Since she hasn't experienced working part-time, everything is new to her. First, she'll be lectured on the proper way of serving customers.
Training her is Matsuno-kun who has a cute smile.
Here's an example!
Welcome! Hello!
This will be your seat.
Please use this for your belongings.
Please take your time.
Fa-fa-fantastic!
First, let's do a simulation.
One person at number 5, please!
Yes!
I'm going to be the customer.
- Please come here!
Yes!
Please use this basket for your belongings.
- Thank you.
It's going smoothly. Do you know what the most important point of serving the customers is?
With a smile!
- That's right! Sakura-kun, it's your greatest weapon, your smile!
It's ok!
- I wonder if it'll be ok. When I face an actual customer... I'll be nervous.
Think of the customers as the people you love.
- Ah, the person you love.
Think of them as fans.
- Right! If you think of them as fans...
By receiving the best advice, all your worries went out the window, right?
You can do it! If it's you, you can do it!
We're going to open!
Please.
- Please.
Opening
Welcome! How would you like Ikkousha's ramen? Welcome! Hello!
What should I be doing?
What should I do?
Her mind goes blank the same time the store opens
Like everyone else, if you could say "welcome" and "thank you."
Uh oh, she's sinking to the back.
Shrinks away because of her nerves
Go, go!
Idol Miyawaki Sakura's smile that mesmerizes the fans.
With a smile.
- If you have that smile.
Before the opening
She overcame unfamiliar, difficult tasks with that smile.
It's fun!
I've never done anything like this before, so I'm having fun.
From that girl...
Her smile vanishes
Welcome! How would you like Ikkousha's ramen?
One person at number 6, please!
It's finally time for her to serve her first customer. It's nerve-racking for us viewers.
- When you see a carry-bag, go to the front.
Ah...
I'm nervous...
- You're feeling nervous, huh?
One person, please!
- Yes!
Can she do well this time around?
Please put your belongings in the basket.
Please take your time.
Did she succeed?
You have to say, "Here, please" first. Once you say that, say, "Please put your belongs in the basket." Please.
This way, please.
Please use the basket.
- Understood.
Please take your time.
Yes, over here, please!
Please use the basket below for your belongings.
Please take your time.
20 Minutes Since Opening
Your seat is over here. Please use the basket for your belongings.
Gradually her Nerves Melt Away
Please take your time.
Miyawaki Sakura's
Over here!
Please use the basket for your belongings.
Usual Smiles Comes Back
Thank you! Thank you!
Your seat is over here.
Like that! Like that! Of course you need to smile!
Sakura-kun, it's been 20 minutes since the opening. How is it?
Eh? It has been only 20 minutes? It's hard.
It's really nerve-racking serving customers.
But I'm finally used to the pace.
It's fun!
It's hard to believe this is her first day. There aren't many people who are able to do as much as her.
She has guts.
She has a better smile than anyone else in my staff.
Thank you very much! Thank you!
Please.
Ai, good!
Did you get used to it.
- Considerably.
40 Minutes Have Passed Since the Opening
Please.
Welcome!
Now Having the Room to Look Around, She...
Do you want me to do it?
- Is that ok?
I'll have you wipe it like this. When that gets too wet, use this.
Personally Asks Someone and Helps Out
She has room to spare now.
We were unsure at first, but you should be fine now.
- If you don't hurry up, we're not gonna make it in time!
After This,
Her Smile Disappears Again
Wah, the store is at its greatest climax.
The afternoon rush.
On its busy days, over 500 people come to the store.
During peak hours, the number of customers won't slow down!
Naturally, the kitchen becomes a battlefield. There are mountains of plates!
Sakura-san, Sakura-san!
Um, I want you to help the washing place.
- Yes, understood.
She moves onto step 3.
She finally heads to the kitchen. The number of dishes that come in during peak hours aren't a joke!
Keep washing, keep washing!
I'll do it once.
You do this.
Keep doing the same task.
Keep doing that. And put the same thing...
In here.
Thank you!
- Thank you!
- If you don't hurry up, we're not gonna make it in time!
The Store is Crowded
It's the busiest time right now.
Please.
This will never end.
The dishes are a bit too piled up. I'll help out.
Hmm, stopping the flow of work is the worst thing you can do.
However, watching from here, you're completely a part of the staff.
I feel sorry because I'm holding them back.
I'm in a hurry...
You're going to start again alone.
Thank you!
- Thank you!
Thank you for washing them. Because you're washing them clean, we can make good ramen.
I'm happy. Thank you. I'll do my best.
You're a really fast learner.
- Really?
It's been one hour since she began washing
You made it clean there, so you can take a break. There's a meal.
- Eh? Really?
Break
It's been four hours since she started working.
Phew, finally a break.
It's really hard.
I was finally getting used to serving people, but washing the dishes felt endless. The dishes kept coming.
Working at a ramen store is harder than being an idol.
Ramen Meal
Here you go!
Wah! It looks good. Itadakimasu.
Itadakimasu.
It's good.
The only thing you're able to say is, "It's good," right? That's fine.
It's good because you worked hard.
Gets Excited Talking About Their Favorite Drinks
Ah, a girl's talk? As expected, you're a normal girl.
End of Break
Thank you for the break.
Thank you.
Sakura-san!
Yes?
I washed the cups, so can you help me wipe them?
Why did you think about joining HKT?
Eh, I was in the world of show business ever since I was child, and during that time...
If I didn't pass the HKT auditions, I was thinking of applying myself more to my studies.
I wanted to be a doctor.
- Is that so? Thank you.
While watching AKB-san, I thought it was lovely being able to make people smile. That's why I auditioned.
- Is that so?
Being supported and loved by everyone.
Grateful, right?
- Honestly grateful.
Excuse me.
Sakura-san!
- Yes!
I'll have you prepare the ingredients now. Take over for the manager.
Eh? You're going to make a newcomer prepare the ingredients?
You'll start preparing the onions for tomorrow.
You'll cut 7 kilograms worth of onions.
The way to cut this... Have you ever used a knife before. Are you ok?
- I have.
Seriously? Seven kilograms of onions?
It's apparently enough to feed 300 people.
Sakura-kun, will you be ok? That's impossible for me.
All you do is drop this side.
You want to do it so that there's some texture when you bite into the fried rice.
Fast!
If you don't finish in 15 minutes, I'm going to scold you.
1-1-15 minutes?! Manager, I think that's impossible!
I'll try my best...
Do your best, at least for the time being.
Ah, what a dangerous way of using your hands. Are you ok?
Your fingers are in danger.
- Don't cut your hand, ok? It'll bleed and we won't be able to use it on TV.
Like you're sliding it. Right, right.
Not like you're dropping it, but like you're moving it forward.
Right, right. Good, good.
Ah, that's good! I've seen something like that on cooking shows.
Oooh, it won't end.
It's been 20 minutes since she began prepping
It's been 20 minutes since she began the task. The store manager is looking at her with forgiving eyes.
Huh?
But...isn't it strange?
Although you're cutting onions, you're not teary-eyed at all!
The tears aren't coming at all.
- Why?
It's probably, um.
I wonder why.
You normally get teary-eyed.
Sakura-chan!
I'm done. I'm done at three, so I'll be going home.
- Thank you for your hard work.
Your trainer, Matsuno-kun, is done with her shift first.
Sakura-kun, will you really be ok with Matsuno-kun?
She's really obedient and when you tell her to do something, she learns it quickly.
Her best quality is her smile. She has a really cute smile and her pureness shines through.
She must be loved by everyone.
Huh, but if you had to name her one quality you're not so sure of?
Not being able to speak loudly. Of course speaking loudly and being lively are really important.
Matsuno-kun, thank you! Your guidance was perfect!
That hat is cute.
It seems like it's going to take a while, so I'm making him help.
- Ah, please.
It's been 30 minutes since she began prepping.
It was decided that she wouldn't be able to finish on time alone, so one of the staff members, Nakanosono-kun, will help out.
Why did you decide to work part-time?
Part-time? That's right.
Well, here at Ikkousha, it's lively and energetic.
- Ah, of course.
I was drawn to that, so I applied.
Asked About His Dreams
I didn't attend a lot of middle or high school.
[T/N]: He mumbles at the very end so I can't understand his reason why
Ah, is that so?
So I want to do something to help those kinds of people.
That's a really lovely dream.
Thank you.
It'll be nice if your lovely dream comes true, Nakanosono-kun. Do your best!
Six hours have passed since she started working
Miyawaki-san, you're done.
- Bad luck!
You couldn't finish the prepping.
Your 6-hour shift at Ikkousha-san is over.
That's why we were able to make something delicious.
He makes fried rice with the onions Sakura-kun chopped up earlier!
My onion!
Fried rice!
Good!
That's good! That's good! That was your brightest smile today!
After the CM,
she finally receives her payment
It's been 6 hours since she started working. Her shift is finally over!
She'll finally receive her long-awaited payment.
Miyawaki-san, thanks for your hard work. You're done.
This is your wages for today. Thank you for today.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
She has a lot of guts. That surprised me.
I thought she might get crushed, especially at the washing area. The washing area is crazy, especially at a ramen store.
She never gave up and did it energetically.
Sorry for holding you all back.
- No, not at all.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
Thank you for today.
Thank you for today. You tried your best!
- Thank you.
Amazing!
4,800 yen.
I earned this!
I'm happy.
It's like...
It's my first time working part-time, and I didn't know just how hard it was going to be.
I've only ever worked as an idol, so
washing the dishes was the hardest.
When my heart was going to break doing that, my senpais told me that I could do it.
With that, I was able to do my best.
It's really, hmm.
I once again realize how hard it was working part-time.
She experienced the difficulties of working.
The happiness and enrichment she was able to obtain there. She capitalized on this experienced and leveled up.
You'll be able to meet a new Miyawaki Sakura!
What does working part-time mean to Sakura-kun?
I'm able to grow more than the person I was yesterday.
For me, it's business.