Original Air Date: 7/17/14
Translated and subbed by: BlueMentaiko
What should I do?
Disclaimer: The translation is not guaranteed to be perfect. Some words and phrases have been slightly altered so it makes more sense in English. Since this is a one-person project, please be understanding of any mistakes I may have made. Thank you!
Work Part-Time And
Repay the Fans
HKT48 was created in Hakata in 2012!
The reason why these girls are nationally active is because they have fans who support them very hard!
The girls will earnestly work part-time
and use the money they earn to create an HKT original umbrella to repay the enthusiastic fans who visit the theater.
This is an unprecedented show!
This time, the member who will work part-time is...
This is HKT48, Team H captain, Anai Chihiro, a.k.a. Chihiron!
Yes! Working part-time today is college student Anai Chihiro-kun, the ponkotsu captain who leads Team H.
Of course, she has no experience working part-time.
It's my first time working part-time.
What's your image of a part-time job?
Well, some of my friends work part-time, and as I thought, it seems hectic and difficult.
Of course. There aren't that many easy jobs out there.
I'll announce the part-time job I want Chihiro-kun to do this time around.
Open!
Pet sitter?
The order is to work earnestly as a pet sitter!
Orders
Pet Sitter
Earnest Part-Time Job
To begin with, do you know what a pet sitter is?
I don't know. Eh, I've heard of it, but...
Animals, right? Like, dogs, cats...taking care of them?
- Roughly speaking, yes.
I'm happy!
I love dogs.
You like dogs?
Yes, I own a dog, so I think I can do it! I said it...
- Saying it is easy.
I'll introduce the person who will be your trainer for today.
Hello.
Hello, please take care of me.
- I'm Pet Service Ii-Smile's Kasai.
Please take care of me.
This person is the shopkeeper of Pet Service Ii-Smile, Kasai-kun.
Focusing on Fukuoka, this pet specialist takes care of dogs, cats, and various other animals in place of their owners.
Kasai-kun, what does a pet sitter do?
We take care of pets in place of owners who cannot do so due to work, being sick, and stuff like that.
That's significant responsibility.
- Yes, that's true.
Right?
- Yes.
Will it be ok?
Let's do our best.
I do love them.
Here they come!
HKT48's serious part-time job documentary!
This time, Anai Chihiro will earnestly work as a pet sitter.
When you're holding this dog, you feel its body temperature, right?
She'll learn about the warmth of animals and the importance of life through this experience. The weight of that will draw out her empathy.
At the same time, she will grow!
You may need a handkerchief this time. Well, a towel or a washcloth is fine, too.
HKT Shakariki 48!
She won't be called a ponkotsu captain any more!
Anai Chihiro
Pet Sitter
Earnest Part-Time Job
Work at last. The house she's heading to has five cute puppies and the mother dog. They're waiting for Chihiro-kun.
Heading to the home whose dogs she will take care of
Part-Time Job Start
Mmm, ruff, ruff!
Isn't it nerve-racking?
Hello!
- Hello!
This is Anai, who will be working part-time today.
- Yes, this is Anai. Please take care of me.
Going to meet the mother dog
Please.
Go ahead.
Please excuse us.
Look, Sakura-chan!
She's called Sakura-chan?
She's a mother.
Cute!
She's docile, isn't she?
Come on!
Next up, the 5 puppies
It's here! Hey!
It's white!
Cute!
These are the five puppies Sakura gave birth to.
Mother Dog Sakura
Five Puppies
Walk and Feed
Feed, Clean Kennel, Playmate
These are the details of taking care of the ultra cute doggies.
From walking Sakura to being the cute puppies' playmate.
First is walking Sakura. Ruff! Ruff!
Walking Start
See you.
We're off!
See you!
Ah, it's excited!
She walks fast!
Fast!
Oh! She suddenly...
She's peeing.
- A lot of urine.
What should I do?
Washing off the urine
Please wash it off.
All right, go ahead.
Chihiro-kun, please wash it off well.
Like that.
Cleanly.
Mhm, it's ok.
Yeah, it's good.
Your performance is pretty good.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
She's shaking. Is she scared?
- What's wrong, Sakura?
What's up, Sakura?
She's scared.
- Sakura!
Sakura, what's wrong? Are you scared?
It's ok.
She's frozen.
What should I do?
Sakura Cowers Suddenly
I own a dog, so...
Eh? I think I can do it!
It's because she's not used to her yet.
She said she owned a dog, but because it was a small breed she didn't walk it often.
It's not like this job is going to be easy because you own a dog!
Because your partner is an animal and cannot speak, being a pet sitter is very hard!
It's ok.
- It's naive because it's a girl.
Mhm, in human years, she's about the same age as Anai-san.
- Because you're a girl, huh?
- Ah! She's young.
You can go now, right? It's not scary.
Let's go.
Let Kasai-san handle her for a while
As expected, at first, the dog is nervous as well.
If you do it two, three times, and keep adding to that, then...
She'll get used to it.
Oh, oh, oh, oh!
- Ah, she's already trying to poop.
Ah, she pooped.
- It's time for this.
Poop time!
Ok, please pick it up.
Do I pick it up little by little?
Honestly, just grab it.
Mhm, just keep putting it in.
Sakura.
That's right, even an idol has to clean up poop.
Is this ok?
Yes, that's fine.
This way.
Is there something I need to be careful of when walking the dog?
Important point of walking
Yes.
The most important thing is not letting any accidents happen to them.
It's the customer's dog, so... Ah, poop again.
Just as she was asking the important points of walking the dog...
It's the second time today.
You're getting good at that!
I'm starting to get used to picking up poop.
Besides not getting into accidents, the other important points are how it walks and checking its physical condition through its excrement.
Previously, Kamaga-san owned a Shepard
Last year, the Shepard passed away due to sickness. Kamaga-san was really dejected.
Kasai-san took custody of Sakura who was at a health center.
And then, Kasai-san convinced Kamaga-san who was really dejected about her Shepard, Nina, passing to take in Sakura.
She was feeling sad about Nina, so I asked her. I halfway forced her to take her.
Then she was like, "I guess it can't be helped" and then took it in.
Furthermore, there was something surprising about Sakura.
I went to the hospital to get rabies shots for her, but then they told me her breasts were a bit full.
When we checked, she had five babies in her stomach.
Kamaga-san is doing really well now.
- That's right.
Pet sitters look after precious life and shorten the distance between animals and humans. They have an important job.
25 minutes since they started walking
Sakura.
She's getting used to you.
Her attitude is completely different now.
Ah, take a right.
Yes.
Stop, stop, stop.
She's quite used to you now and is becoming her ordinary self.
- I'm glad.
Almost home
Let's go this way.
Just a little more.
Fast.
You're fast, we're here.
Walk End
Let's prepare her meal.
Looks good!
- That's for Sakura.
Go to Sakura.
- To Sakura.
Sakura!
Put it next to her water bowl.
Next to her water.
- Tell her to wait.
Wait!
Is it ok?
All right! Go ahead!
She's eating.
Next, the food for the puppies.
Next, the food for the puppies
For the puppies, yes.
Energetic, energetic.
Ok, ok, ok, ok.
It dropped it.
They eat faster than Sakura.
Grow to be big!
Sorry.
Ah! Hey!
Hold on.
All right!
Ok!
Amazing.
48 minutes since she started working
Hey, c'mere.
They're coming!
They're really licking me.
Don't fight.
It's fun.
I'm starting to understand how to be relaxed around them.
I'm very happy.
Whether it's a human or a dog, kids are really cute!
Actually, one of these puppies will go to a foster home today.
This one.
We're taking this one to her foster home right now.
Right now?
- Yes.
Carry just this one.
She'll say goodbye. Your job is to deliver her.
I'll properly deliver her. It's important.
The next important task is delivering this female dog to her foster parents.
It's finally time to say goodbye.
Sakura!
Today will be goodbye.
It's time to say goodbye.
It's like giving away your cute daughter for marriage.
It's like, "Thank you for taking care of me."
I honestly want her to find happiness.
You're going to do your best, right?
Here I go! Bye-bye!
- Thank you. Bye-bye!
Let's go.
Finally going to the foster house
Chihiro-kun is tasked with the important job of delivering one of the puppies to her foster home.
After saying farewell and setting off on the trip, complex feelings rise.
It's somewhat painful.
Arrives at the foster house
Hello!
Thank you for today.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
- Thank you.
I prepared a collar for her.
- Ah, how nice!
This lover of dogs, Somehara-san, owns a dog.
This small life is going to become a member of a new household today.
All right, got it. How cute!
See you!
Yes, thank you.
I'm glad, I'm glad!
Stay healthy and live a happy life.
Thank you.
Tetomu, over here.
Come here.
By the way, she named her Uran. Tetomu, please take care of Uran!
Heads to the next house
All right, we're going to keep going!
Next, the Labrador Retriever, Momochan, is waiting for them.
Um, the owners aren't here.
The owners are not here so they received the key beforehand
They're not here?
Yes. Momo!
Momochan!
This is Momochan.
Hello.
Momo wags her tail like she was waiting for Chihiro-kun all along.
Her job is to walk and feed her.
- She's happy!
I'm glad.
- She's happy because she's wagging her tail that much.
Happy?
Say hello.
Hello.
- Hello.
She's popular.
To the camera.
Umm, I need to go to the next place to prepare for a bit, so I'll leave you alone with her for a while.
- Alone? Ok.
It's all right. Momochan listens to you.
Momochan.
It's just you and me.
From here, she'll finally walk the dog alone.
Momo, we're trusting you with Chihiro-kun!
She's starting to get used to me.
She occasionally looks at my face.
That's how she recogniz- hahaha.
Momochan.
Ah, Momochan, your friend.
Your friend.
Momochan, this way.
Just a little more.
All right, we're here!
Walk Ends
We're home.
Let's wipe your feet.
Welcome back.
We're back.
Thanks for your hard work.
- We're back.
Next is feeding
That's good.
Shake!
Good girl!
Not yet!
Chu!
Momochan.
Cute.
She's eating really fast.
This is the report form.
A report is required for this house
If you're personality comes out, then it'll be good.
Ah, here?
If Chihiro-kun writes honestly about how she felt about Momo's condition and the details of her job, that will be ok.
Ok! I did the report!
I think it's fine.
- I'm glad.
I wonder if it's ok.
People who fill it out to the very last line have a serious personality.
Woah, you wrote, you wrote! It's thorough and good!
"She kissed me and I was really happy about." It's girly and your personality is coming out.
They close up and part with Momo
Bye-bye! Thank you!
Bye-bye!
- Until next time!
It's crying. Meow.
After this, ponkotsu captain versus a cat
The last job
We'll do our last job at this house. So far you've only taken care of dogs, but
this place has cats.
- Cat-chan.
They have five cats.
- They have five?
It's finally the last job! First is feeding the cat and cleaning its litter box.
Feeding
Cleaning the litter box (2 places)
Check for the 5 cats
Your next partner is a cat.
To work independently on your job, Chihiro-kun, we'll make you work alone!
We only told her the location of the litter box and the food. The kind Kasai-kun must become a devil and refrain from giving her any advice.
The owners are not here so they received the key beforehand
Do it earnestly!
This place...
Which one is it?
This?
Is this it?
Found it.
They'll come eat on their own.
Mhm, she's lining them up neatly. That's good.
Food, ok.
The litter box.
Was the next thing the litter box?
- Don't ask that.
We're telling you it's the food and the litter box.
Eh, how much?
Ok!
Under the stairs...
There it is!
Ok.
Feeding
Cleaning the litter box (2 places)
Check for the 5 cats
It's not ok yet. It's not over yet!
There are five cats in this house.
You need to check on the welfare of the cats!
Hidden in every nook and cranny of the house
Cats, in particular, are hard to find.
Look in every nook and cranny!
Ah, there it is.
There it is!
Cat-chan.
Hello.
The first one... Clear.
One.
Ah, there it is!
- The second one...
You were able to check up on it.
They're not here.
Three more.
Heads to the 2nd floor to look for the remaining 3
Ah, there it is!
There it is!
Ah, it hid away!
Cats do their own thing.
I see its face.
- Ohhh, there it is!
One more.
Only one more left
It's like it's playing hide and go seek.
You have to check every nook.
There it is!
Ah, there it is!
There's its butt!
Eh, where is it?
Where is it?
- Found it!
I can't see it well, but we'll trust Chihiro-kun and say the mission is cleared.
Finding the 5 cats completed
You were able to find them quickly!
Even Kasai-kun couldn't find them all in the beginning.
Maybe you're suited for this job.
Are you done?
Yes, I'm done.
Then I'll have you watch them.
Kasai-san's check
All right, it's good.
It's ok!
This?
Entrance, ok.
I'm done!
Thank you for today.
Part-Time Job Done
- Is it ok?
Thank you very much.
It was harder than I expected.
Was it harder than you expected?
Yes.
This is your paycheck for today.
Part-Time job's payment
Please spend it wisely.
- Is it all right? Thank you very much.
Thank you very much.
Yatta!
I'm so happy.
When I first met Anai-san, I was a bit worried because you were so skinny.
But that worry went away and you turned out to be a splendid person.
- I'm glad, thank you.
Thank you for today.
- Thank you for today.
Thanks for today!
- Thank you for today!
You're curious about what's inside, right?
I'm really curious.
Is it all right?
Excuse me.
There was 80,000 yen.
I feel the importance of this money.
I was making light of it at first. I thought taking care of dogs would be easy.
I was like, "Is it going to be cute?"
But it was a lot of responsibility.
She was able to experience the difficulty of working and the importance of life.
Having experienced this, we'll certainly meet a better Anai Chihiro.
Say goodbye to being a ponkotsu!
Finally, what does working part-time mean to Chihiro-kun.
Working is good.
Then work forever.