Original Air Date: 7/31/14
Translated and subbed by: BlueMentaiko
But the men's room is strange.
Disclaimer: The translation is not guaranteed to be perfect. Some words and phrases have been slightly altered so it makes more sense in English. Since this is a one-person project, please be understanding of any mistakes I may have made. Thank you!
It started with this one word...
Let's all do a part-time job to repay the fans!
Work Part-Time And
Repay the Fans
HKT48 was created in Hakata in 2011!
The reason why these girls are nationally active is because they have fans who support them very hard!
Conceived by HKT48's theater manager, Sasshi-kun, the idea is that the girls will earnestly work part-time
and use the money they earn to create an HKT original umbrella to repay the enthusiastic fans who visit the theater.
This is an unprecedented show!
All right, which member will work part-time this time around?
Good morning.
Working part-time today is Kodama Haruka, Hakata's fairy who is innocent and a genius at working hard.
She has no experience working part-time.
What is your image of a part-time job?
Eh? Its image?
There's an hourly wage!
- Yes, yes, hourly wages, daily wages, there are various things like that.
Of course, with the money you earn, you will...
I want to go eat some delicious foods.
- Huh?!
Don't be half asleep! You're supposed to be repaying the precious fans, remember?
Your brain seems to be in sleep mode, so open your eyes right up with today's part-time job. Open!
I see.
The part-time job I'll be doing is...
A karaoke store.
Karaoke Store
Earnest Part-Time Job
Work earnestly at a karaoke store!
What's your image of working part-time at a karaoke store?
- Karaoke?
Eh, but I've only seen them work at the front, so I want to know what they do behind-the-scenes.
Do you go to karaoke often?
I do! I go with members, too.
Oh, what kind of songs do you sing?
Eh, of course Suki! Suki! Skip! at first.
- I see. Sing a bit for us.
...Is how it starts.
- 3 out of 100 points.
Difficult.
HKT48's serious part-time job documentary!
Today, Kodama Haruka will earnestly work part-time at a karaoke store.
What happened in
the men's room!?
By working part-time, she'll learn the difficulty of
working and earning money.
She'll grow both as an idol and as a person. Don't miss it!
The people watching this, do you like karaoke?
HKT Shakariki 48!
Doesn't it make you happy when a really good-looking guy is bad at singing?
Karaoke Store
Earnest Part-Time Job
Today's stage is Korokke Club, Akkerakan Daimeyouten.
It's a, it's a, karaoke store!
With the latest karaoke system and a colorful, restaurant-level menu, it warmly welcomes those who are proud of their voice.
During the weekend, many men and women of all ages visit.
Haruka-kun will earnestly work at this well-established store!
I was able to say it.
Arrives at the job
I'm Kodama Haruka. Please take care of me.
- I'm Zouza, the store manager. Please take care of me today.
Greeting her is the store manager, Zouza-kun.
He will also train Haruka-kun today. Please take care of her!
Hospitality Duties
Kitchen Duties
Other
Receive Customers
Phone Support (Receive Orders)
Carry Drinks, Snacks
Make Drinks, Snacks
Cleanup
Clean Toilet
This is the details of the job.
Karaoke stores are a service business. She first needs to learn the standard greeting.
Well, well, as an idol, this should come easy to Haruka-kun.
Welcome!
- Welcome!
Yes, certainly.
- Yes, certainly.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
Please come again.
- Please come again.
Yes, it's fine.
- I'm glad!
The important point is interacting with customers with a smile. Please don't forget that.
- Understood.
Kodama-san, please decide your goal for today.
Set up goal for today
My goal is to...
To do my best with a smile.
- To do your best with a smile.
Ok, I'll be watching you until the end, so please take care of me.
- Please.
Haruka-kun set up a goal and is in full determination mode.
Do your best for the precious fans!
Part-time job begins
Coached on how to carry drinks and snacks first
First, use just your left hand for the trey.
With one hand?
- Yes.
Hold the trey and do this.
Excuse me.
- Excuse me.
Practice in an unattended room
I brought melon juice and a cola.
Will that be all?
Excuse me.
Then, "excuse me."
- Excuse me.
Look over here to see if the AC power is off.
Next, she is coached on how to cleanup
Next, she gets coached on how to cleanup.
As a general rule, she must cleanup completely so that the next customer can use the room comfortably.
Haruka-kun seems to have no problem with this task.
You seem fine.
- Seems fine.
With that, you're done.
Next up, cleaning the washroom. We assumed that because she is an idol, she has never done this before.
However, this is what she says.
When we're cleaning the theater, I always clean the washroom.
Ah, that's great.
Huh, what? You do it often?
Then let's have you do it!
From now, you'll do the fourth floor men's room.
- Eh? I'm going to do the men's room?
It doesn't matter.
- Understood.
Let's go.
Kodama Haruka's first time in the men's room
In here, there are paper towels and stuff.
Kodama Haruka VS Toilet Basin
Let's try it.
- Please.
I can't use the toilet paper properly.
You have to get used to it, right?
Cleaning is very straightforward.
But the men's room is strange.
Lastly...
- Triangle.
Ah, you noticed. You're right.
The toilet is good.
We're done.
- You're fine, right?
This time, she will clean alone
The water...
All right!
All that is left is...
Should I do this one, too?
Urinal
An idol will clean a urinal.
This is a rare, precious clip.
Woah! It responded!
This is strange.
What's the difference?
Surreal.
This is funny.
If I step away, will it properly flush?
An idol who shows interest
It flushed.
Wow, this is funny.
You are a girl, so you don't stand in front of the urinal, right?
Check
All right, it's good!
- Thank you.
Good for you!
Cleaning the men's room was somewhat of a good experience!
Receptionist duty
Of course, I think you've been to a karaoke store before.
- Ah, yes I have.
When you're receiving someone, you want them to write down their name and phone number.
On weekdays, there's a nine hour maximum all-you-can-use course.
There is a form for this point card.
The number of people and...
And the time.
The number of people and the time.
Welcome. With one person?
The store manager's example
What would the time be? One hour, two hours, or the normal?
The drink bar...?
- If you want to add the drink bar, it will cost 400 yen more.
With the drink bar. Yes.
Please fill out your name and address.
That was really smooth.
Wherever the order is sent from will flash red, so press that.
Coached on how to interact on the phone
If the customer orders one green tea and one melon soda, then you must repeat the order to them afterwards.
Ask if that would be all.
Then you say, "Certainly, please wait." Then the order is done.
For the key, do it after you've opened it.
- Yes, understood.
Try taking it.
Excuse me. This is Kodama from the front.
One orange juice.
Will that be all?
Yes, certainly. Please wait.
Now...that's right.
You cannot hang up before the customer.
Yes, certainly. Please wait.
Please be careful next time.
- Understood.
I've done a lot of handshake events, so I thought I'd be good at serving customers, but...
Difficult.
I can't simultaneously do this and that.
From here, she will work alone!
From here, she will interact with customers alone
You'll be all alone!
Welcome!
Oh, oh, the customers are here at once.
How many people will it be?
- Four people.
How long would you like?
Two hours.
- Two hours. Understood.
How about a drink bar?
You can either do a one-drink order system or have a drink bar.
Then the drink bar.
- Yes, a drink bar.
Do you have a card?
We don't have one.
- You don't have one.
I can make one now free of charge. Would you like one?
Please.
Please fill this out.
Your name and address, please.
Good, good, you're following the manual.
Zouza-san!
Needs help operating the computer
Please help with the computer thing.
The computer thing?
What do you mean by "thing?"
It will be on the fifth floor, room number 509.
Please relax and take your time.
Store manager Zouza-kun, how was it?
It's not like I have to re-coach her.
For a beginner, I think she's doing pretty well.
- Wah, I'm happy!
If you had to grade her?
Well...
How much? About 70%.
I'm thinking about how much you'll grow.
Ah, thank you.
- You're just starting.
Aren't you being a bit soft on idols?
In one year, can you become a master?
No, it's not that easy.
Eh? There are still things you don't know after a year? Oh, it came!
Excuse me. This is Kodama from the front.
Two orange juice.
Two calpis.
One takoyaki.
Calpis and?
Kitchen work
Calpis and orange juice.
The order is? Yes, that's it.
Put in four cubes of ice.
Four?
Is that decided?
- Yes.
Wah, this is nerve-racking.
Knock, knock.
Excuse me.
Calpis and...
Orange juice.
Would that be all for the drinks?
Certainly.
Excuse me.
I did it.
Was that ok?
Next, she makes the takoyaki
Drop it into the oil.
Please put it here.
Finally, the scallions.
Yes, that's right on the mark.
- Looks delicious.
Then let's bring it.
Excuse me.
Ah, thank you!
Apparently they recognized her
This is scallion mayo takoyaki.
They were singing Melon Juice! I'm happy!
I did it!
- You did it?
I think you may be tired now, so go ahead and take a break.
- Understood. Thank you.
Break
Confirm the number of people and the time.
Written on the paper.
It's hard because there's a lot to remember.
A while back, the store manager gave you a 70%, but...
I'd like to get a 100% in this second half.
Well, of course she is an idol, so she has a good smile and courage. In regard to that, it's perfect.
Do you think she will be able to do more in the second half?
I think she'll do it.
I believe that idols are strong during the real thing, so yes.
She works hard even during her break.
Do your best in the second half, too!
No, you have to do it!
Kodama Haruka will sing enthusiastically
Karaoke Store
Earnest Part-Time Job
Resume working
Please relax and take your time.
Excuse me. This is Kodama from the front.
Hello. Welcome!
Ah, how many people will it be?
Two people.
- Ah, two people.
How long would you like?
One hour.
- One hour.
Please fill out your name and address here.
Certainly.
It will be on the fifth floor, room number 509.
Please relax and take your time.
They don't have the drink bar, so they'll probably call you shortly.
- That's right, an order will come.
My memo pad is gone. Oh, there it is.
Excuse me. This is Kodama from the front.
Two Dekavitas.
Certainly. Please wait.
Excuse me.
This is Dekavita C.
Yes, thank you.
Thank you.
Will that be all?
Excuse me. Can you sing...
Can you sing one song for us?
- A song?
Had recognized Kodama
Please!
Is it ok?
- Please sing.
Yes.
Really?
- It's ok.
I wonder if it's ok. Oh well.
What will you like to sing?
Eh, what? What would be good?
HKT's song.
Like Melon Juice?
- Ah, please.
Apparently will sing seriously
Eh, amazing.
I'm nervous!
Hey! Is this ok?
Oh my, the intro is starting!
After this, Kodama Haruka independent live
Done.
Cute!
- It's hot!
All right, 100%! No, no time for that!
Hurry up and return to work!
Excuse me.
Please relax and take your time.
That surprised me.
I don't take the stairs often, so this is tiring.
Excuse me.
Finally, this is her last task.
From here, please watch an idol clean a room.
The state of the cleanup
Then the bottom.
Is this ok?
'Kay.
Wah, I feel like I'm going to fall. Scary.
It's ok, it's ok.
Cleaning up is difficult.
And then
Kodama-san!
That's enough for today.
- Thank you.
Finishes work
You're done for today.
Part-time job payment
This is your pay for today.
- Thank you.
Please use it wisely.
- Yes, I understand.
I'll use it wisely. Thank you.
She was cheerful and listened to me obediently, so she was easy to teach.
You gave her a 70% in the first half. Right now, how would you grade her?!
That's right. Well, 90%, no, 99%.
There's next time, so I can't give her a perfect score.
A 99%!
You may have a different opinion on this, but shut up!
You did well, Haruka-kun! And how about that one thing?
4,250 yen!
Ah, but I'm glad I worked hard.
When you receive payment.
At first, I was bewildered.
I was like, "Ahhh, what should I do?!"
But once I got used to it, it became really fun.
And when things went smoothly, I was able to be like, "Ah, yatta!" This sense of accomplishment was really nice.
I'd like to do different part-time jobs again.
Haruka-kun, before you started working, you created a goal for yourself, right?
To do my best with a smile.
I think I was able to achieve that.
How would you grade yourself today?
For myself?
100%!!
- Huh?!
She experienced the difficulty of working.
The happiness and sense of fulfillment she was able to obtain...
Having experienced this, we'll certainly meet a better Kodama Haruka.
Kodama-kun, what does working part-time mean to you?
A place where I could expand my possibilities.
100%.